tcunet.com 2003-06-02

# privacy statement

| 

Privacy Statement

Our Privacy Policy  
**WHO “WE” ARE:  
**In this brochure, “we” means  
• **Teachers Credit Union** \- A credit union located in South Bend, Indiana, serving members in 50 states  
• **TCU Travel LLC** \- A subsidiary of Teachers Credit Union, offering a travel agency to members and non members of Teachers Credit Union.  
• **TCU Investment Services LLC,** a subsidiary to Teachers Credit Union offering securities, brokerage, financial planning, insurance products and services to members and non members of Teachers Credit Union, and  
• **TCU Agency LLC** \- A subsidiary to Teachers Credit Union, offering insurance products.  
We are “affiliates” of each other.  
**WHAT THIS IS:  
**This disclosure is the privacy policy for all entities above (us). We are combining this disclosure because our policies are similar; you might be a member/client of more than one of us; and, if you opt out, your opt out will affect each of us.   
In this brochure, we will tell you (among other things):  
Where we get information about you (our sources);   
with whom we might share any of that information, and why;   
what you can do if you don’t want us to share certain information about you and   
what we do to protect the information we have about you from unintended users.  
**WHO “YOU” ARE:  
**This policy applies to our consumer members/clients who have continuing relationships with one (or more) of us.  
You have a continuing relationship with the Credit Union if, for example, you have a  
• Deposit (share) account • Internet Service (Home Banking/Account Aggregation) • Retail installment contract we hold and service  
• Loan account • Safe deposit box • Self-directed Individual Retirement Account   
• Credit card • Automobile lease we service where we act as custodian  
You have a continuing relationship with the TCU Travel LLC, TCU Investment Services LLC, or TCU Agency, LLC if you, for example purchase an insurance policy, create a brokerage account, or obtain financial planning services from or through one of these affiliates.  
**MORE DEFINITIONS:  
**“ **Information** ” means “nonpublic personal information,” which is a technical term that generally means information that can identify you; that is not available publicly; and that we collect in connection with providing a financial product or service to you.   
We will use the word “information” in this brochure to mean “nonpublic personal information.”  
**Affiliate** is a company one of us owns, a company that owns one of us, or a company that is owned or controlled by a company that owns one of us. The Credit Union, the TCU Travel LLC, TCU Investment Services LLC, and TCU Agency, LLC are affiliates of each other.  
**Nonaffiliate** includes a person who is not employed by one of us, or a company that is not an affiliate.  
**Opt out** means a choice you make to prevent us from sharing information about you with others.  
**JOINT ACCOUNTS:**  
If you have a joint account with us, you should share this notice with the persons who share your account. They may not get a separate notice. You may only get one of these disclosures, no matter how many of us you have an account with, and no matter how many accounts you might have. (The number of such disclosures might depend on how our computer sorts information we have about you.)  
**SOURCES FOR INFORMATION:**  
Each of us collects information about our members/clients from the following sources:   
Information you might provide on applications and other forms;   
Information about transactions one of us might conduct for you;  
Information about transactions you might conduct through an affiliate; or   
Information about your transactions with nonaffiliated third parties.  
The Credit Union also may collect information about you from a consumer reporting agency.  
**THE CONFIDENTIALITY, SECURITY, AND INTEGRITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**  
Each of us restricts access to information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. Each of us maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to guard your information. Federal regulations require such safeguards.  
**INFORMATION WE DISCLOSE ABOUT YOU BETWEEN US (WITH AFFILIATES):  
****Transaction information:  
**We may share the following types of information about you with each other (affiliates) derived from the transactions either (or all) of us conducts on your behalf:   
name, address, account balances, account activity, types of accounts, deposit history, parties to the transaction, phone number, age  
Federal law allows us to share information derived from the transactions we do for you with each other. You do not have a right to opt out of the sharing of this information.  
**Non transaction information:  
**We share between us the following information, derived from applications and other forms submitted by customers, such as assets and income.  
Members/clients of each entity can opt out of the sharing of this information listed immediately above (taken from applications and other forms).   
The instructions for and the effect of an opt out are below.   
**Reasons For Disclosure  
**We share the information listed above between us so our members/clients can be aware of all the financial products that we offer through all our entities.   
**JOINT MARKETING**  
We may disclose the following information to other financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements:  
Information from applications and other forms, such as name, address, social security number, deposit balances, and loan balances.  
**Exceptions:  
**The Credit Union does not share information about members located in Alabama, Alaska, Idaho, North Dakota and Vermont for joint marketing purposes.  
The Credit Union does not share information derived from deposit accounts about members located in Massachusetts, Mississippi and New Jersey.   
**Types of Businesses  
**The credit union provides this information for joint marketing purposes to financial service providers, such as securities broker-dealers, insurance or title insurance companies and private label (TCU Card) credit card issuers.  
**Reasons For Disclosing  
**We may disclose information about you pursuant to joint marketing agreements so we can provide you with information about additional products and services that we might not be able to offer you ourselves but which we can offer you together with others.  
**YOUR INFORMATION AND OTHER PARTIES  
**We will not disclose information about you to anyone except as disclosed in this policy or as permitted by law.  
**INFORMATION ABOUT FORMER MEMBERS  
**We have the same policy about disclosing information about former members as we do about current members.  
**YOUR RIGHT TO BLOCK THE DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION - INSTRUCTIONS AND EFFECT  
**You have the right to ask us not to share between us the information derived from sources other than the transactions we conduct on your behalf, as mentioned earlier. This is referred to as an opt out. If you wish to opt out of disclosures, you may do so by calling 800-552-4745 or complete and return a form which you can obtain at our website at www.tcunet.com  
If you have one or more joint accounts, an opt out instruction given by one participant of such an account will affect all of the accounts of the person who opts out and all information from those accounts about others who participate in those accounts. An opt out instruction will apply to all of us. This means that an opt out will prevent the Credit Union from sharing the non transaction information with TCU Travel LLC, TCU Investment Services LLC, and TCU Agency LLC, and them from sharing the same information with the Credit Union, or each other. An opt out will remain in effect until you change it, or the law changes and we give you further notice of that change.  

Rev. 2/03
